KEVIN MADDEN

45 Balliol Street, Toronto · 647-884-0560

kmadden84@gmail.com · https://www.linkedin.com/in/kevin-madden-12865035
https://www.kevinmadden.info

I'm an experienced web development professional with many years' experience in front-end web development

I am well-versed in HTML5, CSS3, vanilla JavaScript, and jQuery, and have experience building REST APIs with Node.js + Express (using ORMs like Mongoose and Sequelize), and single-page apps with React/Native, Redux, Context API and React Hooks. I'm also well versed in tools including Git, GitHub Desktop, Visual Studio Code, MS Office, JIRA, Confluence, Slack, Zendesk, Google Analytics, and Webmaster Tools. I take pride in having exceptional verbal and written communication skills.

My goal is to find a full-time position in a rewarding, challenging work environment.

EXPERIENCE

NOVEMBER 2021 - PRESENT

FRONT END DEVELOPER, GOODFOOD

- Setup Google Tag Manager for integration with Google Universal Analytics, Google Analytics 4, and other 3rd party Analytics applications (Emarsys). This includes writing GTM-side scripts to extract information from the site that isn't being pushed to the data layer.
- Updating a recent revision of their website built with React/NextJS to push relevant information to the GTM Data Layer, so this data is available for analytics purposes. This includes creating custom events, triggers and data in the front-end code. I also need to ensure proper formatting of the data to ensure its acceptance in third party applications.
- Updated Analytics documentation in Confluence.
- Updates the desktop site as needed (NextJS with Context)
- Updated their app as needed, building out components, functionality, and fixing bugs.

JANUARY 2021 - NOVEMBER 2021

FRONT END DEVELOPER, BOUNTEOUS

- Create custom pages on Wawa.com for various campaigns, as well as general site layout updates and improvements. Kentico based CMS, and updates were made using HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, and Sass/CSS.
- Used React to create an Allergens page for Wawa users would select from a set of allergens, which would query an API and return a list of foods containing selected allergens. Table contained filtering and dropdown capabilities.
- Create responsive emails for various campaigns and test them using Litmus.
- Carve assets out of .psd files for various updates to Wawa's in-store ordering terminals

NOVEMBER 2019 – JANUARY 2021

FRONT END DEVELOPER/SITE PRODUCTION SPECIALIST, BELL

- Primarily update/create pages for Bell Mobility using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and jQuery
- Coordinate with clients and stakeholders to deliver timely delivery of website content
- In my personal time during this role, I have taken the opportunity to continue to develop my Node.js and React skills, building new apps, APIs, and upgrading rebuilding my personal website using React and Node.

MAY 2019 – NOVEMBER 2019

SUPPORT ROCKSTAR, FRESHBOOKS

- Respond to client inquiries via phone and tickets
- Provide solutions based on client needs
- Troubleshoot technical issues (email issues, software syncing, caching issues)
- Built a FreshBooks extension app in React, Node.js, Express, and Sequelize to interact with FreshBooks and increase its stock management capabilities.

JUNE 2014 - FEBRUARY 2019

FRONT END DEVELOPER/WEB SUPPORT ANALYST, Q4 INC

- Primary role at Q4 was to maintain and update company Investor Relations websites and apps. Worked with companies including Best Buy, Wal-Mart, LinkedIn, Nike, Shopify, Apple and other large Fortune 500 IR teams.
- Worked with IR and Marketing Teams to design and update web content, and distribute emails to large subscriber bases.
- Updated and built websites using HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, and JavaScript
- Update photos and graphics with Photoshop
- Build out custom functionality as required
- Build site pages from Photoshop mock-ups
- Troubleshoot website-related issues
- Update sites to ensure WCAG compliance (ARIA labels, title tags, alt tags, contrast toggles, etc...)
- Optimize SEO using meta, alt, and title tags, site-speed optimization, as well as using sitemaps via Webmaster Tools, Google Analytics & Search Console, 301 redirects, and more
- Work to ensure WCAG Compliance
- Draft emails in HTML/CSS and distribute to client email subscribers
- January 2018: Moved to a Front-End React Role. This involved upgrading/modernizing the Q4 CMS user interface and enhancing functionality and usability.

NOVEMBER 2010 - MAY 2014

WEBMASTER/OFFICE MANAGER/SOFTWARE QA, SIGMAXL INC

- Update the website, optimizing SEO and software help documentation
- Manage Google Adwords and Bing Ads accounts
- Managing Social Media presence (Twitter, Facebook, LinkedIn)
- Ensure smooth day-to-day operations of the office
- Interview and hire new employees
- Handle accounts payable, payroll, generate invoices
- Train new employees
- Manage client requests via Microsoft Exchange
- Handle escalated client issues
- Implement process improvements for a more efficient client support process
- Test software to ensure compliance with workbook
- Assist clients in both using and troubleshooting software
- Assist clients with data analysis using SigmaXL's statistics software
- Process sales and orders; generating invoices
- Creating, editing, and compressing videos

AUGUST 2009 – OCTOBER 2010

TECHNICAL SUPPORT/CUSTOMER RETENTION, BELL FIBE TV

- Assist clients having issues with their Internet, and Internet-based television service
- Upgrade and sell TV packages
- Use remote-desktop software to troubleshoot modem and router issues
- Attempt to win back customers using promotional offers.

SEPTEMBER 2008 – MARCH 2009

BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT REP, AMERICAN EXPRESS

- Consultative sales
- Speak with American small-business owners to assess business needs, and position various American Express charge cards based on those needs

EDUCATION

JUNE 2010

FULL STACK JAVASCRIPT, TREEHOUSE

Certificate of Completion

SEPTEMBER 2007

BACHELOR OF ARTS, SIMON FRASER UNIVERSITY

Majored in Criminology

SKILLS

- Strong HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery
- React/Redux, Node.JS, Express, Pug
- Client Relationship Management

- Customer support and team management
- Google Analytics, AdWords, General SEO